* * Pokémon
    * * Mechanics
    * * Games
    * * TCG
        * [Rotation](https://bulbapedia.bulbagarden.net/wiki/Rotation_(TCG))
        * [Promotional Cards](https://bulbapedia.bulbagarden.net/wiki/Promotional_cards_(TCG))
        * [Surging Sparks](https://bulbapedia.bulbagarden.net/wiki/Surging_Sparks_(TCG))
        * [Stellar Crown](https://bulbapedia.bulbagarden.net/wiki/Stellar_Crown_(TCG))
        * [Shrouded Fable](https://bulbapedia.bulbagarden.net/wiki/Shrouded_Fable_(TCG))
        * [Twilight Masquerade](https://bulbapedia.bulbagarden.net/wiki/Twilight_Masquerade_(TCG))
    * * Animation & Manga
        * [Pokémon Horizons](https://bulbapedia.bulbagarden.net/wiki/Pok%C3%A9mon_Horizons:_The_Series_(season))
    * * Social
    * * Apps

    * * Bulbapedia
    * * Archives
    * * New Accounts

Menu

**[Our 2024 Holiday Season Contests have begun](https://bulbagarden.net/threads/bulbagarden-holiday-contests-2024.304346/)! [Click here to check out how you could win a share in over $2000 USD of amazing prizes](https://bulbagarden.net/threads/bulbagarden-holiday-contests-2024.304346/)!**  
Please remember to follow the **[unreleased materials policy](https://bulbapedia.bulbagarden.net/wiki/Bulbapedia:Unreleased_materials_policy "Bulbapedia:Unreleased materials policy")**, **[manual of style](https://bulbapedia.bulbagarden.net/wiki/Bulbapedia:Manual_of_style "Bulbapedia:Manual of style")**, and **[code of conduct](https://bulbapedia.bulbagarden.net/wiki/Bulbapedia:Code_of_conduct "Bulbapedia:Code of conduct")** at all times.  
Check the [Bulbagarden home page](https://bulbagarden.net/) for up-to-date Pokémon news, and discuss it on the [forums](https://bulbagarden.net/forums/) or in the [Bulbagarden Discord server](https://discord.gg/bulbagarden).

Bulbapedia:Privacy policy
=========================

From Bulbapedia, the community-driven Pokémon encyclopedia.

Bulbagarden recognizes the importance of protecting the privacy of all information provided by users of Bulbagarden. We created the following policy guidelines with a fundamental respect for our users' right to privacy. Bulbagarden ("us", "we", or "our") operates Bulbapedia ([https://bulbapedia.bulbagarden.net](https://bulbapedia.bulbagarden.net/)), Bulbanews ([https://bulbanews.bulbagarden.net/](https://bulbanews.bulbagarden.net/)), the Bulbagarden Archives ([https://archives.bulbagarden.net/wiki/Main\_Page](https://archives.bulbagarden.net/wiki/Main_Page)), the Bulbagarden Handbooks ([http://bulbahandbook.bulbagarden.net/](http://bulbahandbook.bulbagarden.net/)), the Bulbagarden forums ([http://forums.bulbagarden.net/index.php](http://forums.bulbagarden.net/index.php)) - collectively, the "Services". This page informs you of our policies regarding the collection, use, and disclosure of personal data when you use our Services and the choices you have associated with that data. We use your data to provide and improve the Service. By using the Service, you agree to the collection and use of information in accordance with this policy.

The policy below is effective as of September 13th, 2022.

Contents
--------

    * [1.6 Data Processors (or Service Providers)](#Data_Processors_(or_Service_Providers))
    * [1.7 Data Subject (or User)](#Data_Subject_(or_User))
    * [3.2 Legal Basis for Processing Personal Data Under General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)](#Legal_Basis_for_Processing_Personal_Data_Under_General_Data_Protection_Regulation_(GDPR))
* [8 Your Data Protection Rights Under General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)](#Your_Data_Protection_Rights_Under_General_Data_Protection_Regulation_(GDPR))

Definitions
-----------

### Service

A Service is any of the Services operated by Bulbagarden. This includes but is not limited to Bulbapedia ([https://bulbapedia.bulbagarden.net](https://bulbapedia.bulbagarden.net/)), Bulbanews ([https://bulbanews.bulbagarden.net/](https://bulbanews.bulbagarden.net/)), the Bulbagarden Archives ([https://archives.bulbagarden.net/wiki/Main\_Page](https://archives.bulbagarden.net/wiki/Main_Page)), the Bulbagarden Handbooks ([http://bulbahandbook.bulbagarden.net/](http://bulbahandbook.bulbagarden.net/)), the Bulbagarden forums ([http://forums.bulbagarden.net/index.php](http://forums.bulbagarden.net/index.php)).

### Personal Data

Personal Data means data about a living individual who can be identified from those data (or from those and other information either in our possession or likely to come into our possession).

### Usage Data

Usage Data is data collected automatically either generated by the use of the Service or from the Service infrastructure itself (for example, the duration of a page visit).

### Cookies

Cookies are files with small amount of data which may include an anonymous unique identifier. Cookies are sent to your browser from a website and stored on your device (computer or mobile device). For more information about cookies please visit [http://www.allaboutcookies.org/cookies/](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/cookies/).

### Data Controller

Data Controller means the natural or legal person who (either alone or jointly or in common with other persons) determines the purposes for which and the manner in which any personal information are, or are to be, processed. For the purpose of this Privacy Policy, we are a Data Controller of your Personal Data.

### Data Processors (or Service Providers)

Data Processor (or Service Provider) means any natural or legal person who processes the data on behalf of the Data Controller. We may use the services of various Service Providers in order to process your data more effectively.

### Data Subject (or User)

Data Subject is any living individual who is using our Service and is the subject of Personal Data.

Types of Data Collected by Bulbagarden
--------------------------------------

Bulbagarden collects information about users during their registration for our newsletter and during their participation in certain activities on our website, including contests. When users request pages from our server, our Web server automatically collects some information about the users, including their IP addresses. These addresses are used by computers on the network to send the requested pages to users.

### Personal Data

While using our Service, we may ask you to provide us with certain personally identifiable information that can be used to contact or identify you ("Personal Data"). Personally identifiable information may include, but is not limited to:

#### Email address

#### Cookies and Usage Data

We may use your Personal Data to contact you with newsletters, marketing or promotional materials and other information that may be of interest to you. You may opt out of receiving any, or all, of these communications from us by following the unsubscribe link or instructions provided in any email we send.

#### Usage Data

We may also collect information how the Service is accessed and used ("Usage Data"). This Usage Data may include information such as your computer's Internet Protocol address (e.g. IP address), browser type, browser version, the pages of our Service that you visit, the time and date of your visit, the time spent on those pages, unique device identifiers and other diagnostic data.

#### Tracking & Cookies Data

We use cookies and similar tracking technologies to track the activity on our Service and hold certain information. Tracking technologies also used are beacons, tags, and scripts to collect and track information and to improve and analyze our Service. You can instruct your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, if you do not accept cookies, you may not be able to use some portions of our Service. Examples of Cookies we use:

* Session Cookies: We use Session Cookies to operate our Service.
* Preference Cookies: We use Preference Cookies to remember your preferences and various settings.
* Security Cookies: We use Security Cookies for security purposes.
* Advertising Cookies: Advertising Cookies are used to serve you with advertisements that may be relevant to you and your interests.

##### "Do Not Track" Signals

We do not currently support Do Not Track ("DNT"), however some third-party advertising companies used by Bulbagarden may support this. Do Not Track is a preference you can set in your web browser to inform websites that you do not want to be tracked. You can enable or disable Do Not Track by visiting the Preferences or Settings page of your web browser.

Use of data
-----------

Bulbagarden uses the collected data for various purposes:

* To provide and maintain our Service
* To notify you about changes to our Service
* To allow you to participate in interactive features of our Service when you choose to do so
* To provide customer support
* To gather analysis or valuable information so that we can improve our Service
* To monitor the usage of our Service
* To detect, prevent and address technical issues
* To provide you with news, special offers and general information about other goods, services and events which we offer that are similar to those that you have already purchased or enquired about unless you have opted not to receive such information

### Cookies & Advertising

Bulbagarden may use user entered information in combination with site usage information to help display advertisements relevant to the users interest and navigation patterns. Bulbagarden may use cookies to help in tracking these patterns but does not store or collect any personal data in combination with user supplied information. Cookies are small text files that contain a string of alphanumeric characters. You can remove cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser’s “help” file. For more information about cookies please visit [http://www.allaboutcookies.org/cookies/](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/cookies/).

### Legal Basis for Processing Personal Data Under General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)

If you are from the European Economic Area (EEA), Bulbagarden's legal basis for collecting and using the personal information described in this Privacy Policy depends on the Personal Data we collect and the specific context in which we collect it. Bulbagarden may process your Personal Data because:

* We need to perform a contract with you
* You have given us permission to do so
* The processing is in our legitimate interests and it's not overridden by your rights
* To comply with the law

Retention of Data
-----------------

Bulbagarden will retain your Personal Data only for as long as is necessary for the purposes set out in this Privacy Policy. We will retain and use your Personal Data to the extent necessary to comply with our legal obligations (for example, if we are required to retain your data to comply with applicable laws), resolve disputes, and enforce our legal agreements and policies. Bulbagarden will also retain Usage Data for internal analysis purposes. Usage Data is generally retained for a shorter period of time, except when this data is used to strengthen the security or to improve the functionality of our Service, or we are legally obligated to retain this data for longer time periods.

Transfer of Data
----------------

Your information, including Personal Data, may be transferred to — and maintained on — computers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the data protection laws may differ than those from your jurisdiction. If you are located outside Norway and choose to provide information to us, please note that we transfer the data, including Personal Data, to Norway and process it there. Your consent to this Privacy Policy followed by your submission of such information represents your agreement to that transfer. Bulbagarden will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this Privacy Policy and no transfer of your Personal Data will take place to an organization or a country unless there are adequate controls in place including the security of your data and other personal information.

Disclosure of Data
------------------

### Business Transaction

If Bulbagarden is involved in a merger, acquisition or asset sale, your Personal Data may be transferred. We will provide notice before your Personal Data is transferred and becomes subject to a different Privacy Policy.

### Disclosure for Law Enforcement

Under certain circumstances, Bulbagarden may be required to disclose your Personal Data if required to do so by law or in response to valid requests by public authorities (e.g. a court or a government agency).

### Legal Requirements

Bulbagarden may disclose your Personal Data in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to:

* To comply with a legal obligation
* To protect and defend the rights or property of Bulbagarden
* To prevent or investigate possible wrongdoing in connection with the Service
* To protect the personal safety of users of the Service or the public
* To protect against legal liability

Security of Data
----------------

Bulbagarden uses reasonable precautions to keep the personal information disclosed to us secure and to disclose such information only to responsible third parties after permission from the user. The security of your data is important to us, but remember that no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage is 100% secure. While we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your Personal Data, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

Your Data Protection Rights Under General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)
---------------------------------------------------------------------------

If you are a resident of the European Economic Area (EEA), you have certain data protection rights. Bulbagarden aims to take reasonable steps to allow you to correct, amend, delete, or limit the use of your Personal Data. If you wish to be informed what Personal Data we hold about you and if you want it to be removed from our systems, please contact us. In certain circumstances, you have the following data protection rights:

* The right to access, update or to delete the information we have on you. Whenever made possible, you can access, update or request deletion of your Personal Data directly within your account settings section. If you are unable to perform these actions yourself, please contact us to assist you.
* The right of rectification. You have the right to have your information rectified if that information is inaccurate or incomplete.
* The right to object. You have the right to object to our processing of your Personal Data.
* The right of restriction. You have the right to request that we restrict the processing of your personal information.
* The right to data portability. You have the right to be provided with a copy of the information we have on you in a structured, machine-readable and commonly used format.
* The right to withdraw consent. You also have the right to withdraw your consent at any time where Bulbagarden relied on your consent to process your personal information.

Please note that we may ask you to verify your identity before responding to such requests. You have the right to complain to a Data Protection Authority about our collection and use of your Personal Data. For more information, please contact your local data protection authority in the European Economic Area (EEA).

Service Providers
-----------------

We may employ third party companies and individuals to facilitate our Service ("Service Providers"), to provide the Service on our behalf, to perform Service-related services or to assist us in analyzing how our Service is used. These third parties have access to your Personal Data only to perform these tasks on our behalf and are obligated not to disclose or use it for any other purpose.

### Analytics

We may use third-party Service Providers to monitor and analyze the use of our Service.

#### Google Analytics

Google Analytics is a web analytics service offered by Google that tracks and reports website traffic. Google uses the data collected to track and monitor the use of our Service. This data is shared with other Google services. Google may use the collected data to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network. You can opt-out of having made your activity on the Service available to Google Analytics by installing the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on. The add-on prevents the Google Analytics JavaScript (ga.js, analytics.js, and dc.js) from sharing information with Google Analytics about visits activity. For more information on the privacy practices of Google, please visit the Google Privacy & Terms web page: [http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)

### Advertising

Bulbagarden may use third-party Service Providers to show advertisements to you when you visit our Web site, to help support and maintain our Service. These companies may use aggregated information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, [click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp).

#### Appodeal

Appodeal, as a third party vendor, serves advertisements to users on our official mobile app. For more information on the privacy practices of Appodeal, please visit the Appodeal privacy policy web page: [https://www.appodeal.com/home/privacy-policy/](https://www.appodeal.com/home/privacy-policy/)

#### Google AdSense & DoubleClick Cookie

Google, as a third party vendor, uses cookies to serve ads on our Service. Google's use of the DoubleClick cookie enables it and its partners to serve ads to our users based on their visit to our Service or other websites on the Internet. You may opt out of the use of the DoubleClick Cookie for interest-based advertising by visiting the Google Ads Settings web page: [http://www.google.com/ads/preferences/](https://www.google.com/ads/preferences/)

#### Google AdWords

Google AdWords remarketing service is provided by Google Inc. You can opt-out of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customize the Google Display Network ads by visiting the Google Ads Settings page: [http://www.google.com/settings/ads](https://www.google.com/settings/ads) Google also recommends installing the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on - [https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout) - for your web browser. Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on provides visitors with the ability to prevent their data from being collected and used by Google Analytics. For more information on the privacy practices of Google, please visit the Google Privacy & Terms web page: [http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)

#### CafeMedia

This Site is affiliated with CMI Marketing, Inc., d/b/a CafeMedia ("CafeMedia") for the purposes of placing advertising on the Site, and CafeMedia will collect and use certain data for advertising purposes. To learn more about CafeMedia's data usage, click here [https://www.cafemedia.com/publisher-advertising-privacy-policy](https://www.cafemedia.com/publisher-advertising-privacy-policy)

#### Behavioral Remarketing

Bulbagarden uses remarketing services to advertise on third party websites to you after you visited our Service. We and our third-party vendors use cookies to inform, optimize and serve ads based on your past visits to our Service.

### Social Media

The collection, use, and disclosure of personal data when you use social media channels associated with Bulbagarden, including but not limited to the Bulbagarden Discord server ([https://discord.gg/bulbagarden](https://discord.gg/bulbagarden)), Facebook page ([https://www.facebook.com/Bulbagarden](https://www.facebook.com/Bulbagarden)), Twitch channel ([https://www.twitch.tv/bulbagarden](https://www.twitch.tv/bulbagarden)), Youtube channel ([https://www.youtube.com/user/Bulbagarden](https://www.youtube.com/user/Bulbagarden)), Twitter accounts ([https://twitter.com/Bulbagarden](https://twitter.com/Bulbagarden), [https://twitter.com/Bulbapedia](https://twitter.com/Bulbapedia), [https://twitter.com/Bulbanews](https://twitter.com/Bulbanews), [https://twitter.com/Bulbanewsnow](https://twitter.com/Bulbanewsnow)), and Tumblr page ([https://bulbagarden.tumblr.com/](https://bulbagarden.tumblr.com/)), are subject to the privacy policies of those respective platforms. Bulbagarden is not responsible for the privacy policies of third-party Service Providers.

Links to Other Sites
--------------------

Our Service may contain links to other sites that are not operated by us. If you click on a third party link, you will be directed to that third party's site. We strongly advise you to review the Privacy Policy of every site you visit. We have no control over and assume no responsibility for the content, privacy policies or practices of any third party sites or services to which we may provide links.

Contests
--------

By entering Bulbagarden contests, users consent to the use of their name or pseudonym in the announcement of the winners on the Bulbagarden website, and use of their name and likeness for advertising and/or promotional and/or marketing purposes. Users' contact information may also be used by Bulbagarden to notify the user they have won and to confirm their mailing address.

Children's Privacy
------------------

If you are a parent or guardian and you are aware that your Children has provided us with Personal Data without your consent, please contact us. If we become aware that we have collected Personal Data from children without parental consent, we take steps to remove that information from our servers.

Changes to This Privacy Policy
------------------------------

We may update our Privacy Policy from time to time. We will notify you of any changes by posting the new Privacy Policy on this page. We will let you know via email and/or a prominent notice on our Service, prior to the change becoming effective and update the "effective date" at the top of this Privacy Policy. You are advised to review this Privacy Policy periodically for any changes. Changes to this Privacy Policy are effective when they are posted on this page.

Contact Us
----------

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please contact us by email: [\[email protected\]](https://bulbapedia.bulbagarden.net/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection)

Retrieved from "[https://bulbapedia.bulbagarden.net/w/index.php?title=Bulbapedia:Privacy\_policy&oldid=3570205](https://bulbapedia.bulbagarden.net/w/index.php?title=Bulbapedia:Privacy_policy&oldid=3570205)"

[Category](https://bulbapedia.bulbagarden.net/wiki/Special:Categories "Special:Categories"):

Navigation menu
---------------

### Page actions

* [View source](https://bulbapedia.bulbagarden.net/w/index.php?title=Bulbapedia:Privacy_policy&action=edit "This page is protected.
    You can view its source [e]")

### Page actions

### Personal tools

### Navigation

### Search

### Bulbagarden

### Social media

### Tools

* [Printable version](javascript:print(); "Printable version of this page [p]")

* This page was last edited on 13 September 2022, at 05:35.
* Content is available under [Attribution-NonCommercial-ShareAlike 2.5](http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/2.5/). (see [Copyrights](https://bulbapedia.bulbagarden.net/wiki/Bulbapedia:Copyrights) for details)
